Hello guys and welcome back, so now in this video we are going to add footsteps to our
zombies and to our player character right, because right now we don't have any footsteps
or game fields that are a little bit empty, alright so in order to add footsteps, first
of all if you check the player for the player the footsteps are already setup as you can
see in this stone, if the player is walking on any stones it will play these are used
and same for grass tiles and untag, alright but the footsteps audio clips are not assigned
for the zombies so if you check any zombie audio clips as you can see they are empty, so
now we need to fix this, in order to do that of course we can't add all of the audio
for each of this, because it will take a lot of time, so what we are going to do instead
is click on the first person character copy the footsteps from here, so click on copy
component and then select all of the zombies and to all of them right here, click three
dots on the footstep and click on paste component values, when you do that now in all
of them the clips are right there, now select the first zombie for the zombie, the left
and right foot is assigned of the player, of course we don't want that we want the zombie
footsteps to be assigned right here okay, so in order to assign it you will have to open
this up left foot, okay let's actually double click on this, alright so left foot right there
alright so we need to add this left foot, so click on zombie and drop this left foot right
there and then you can do the same for the right foot, alright let's do it for the next
zombie which is this one, so open this up, so here is the left foot and then the right
foot, here it is, right you can go ahead and do this for all of the other zombies, so once
you do it for all of these zombies now it will not play any footsteps sound first, we have
to do few changes, okay the first one is we want the cross, how do you to play whenever
we are walking on this terrain world, so if you click on this terrain okay this is the terrain
right here make sure that you change its layer to default, alright and make sure that you
tag this as cross, okay because there are cross everywhere on the terrain, so we will be
playing the cross footsteps sound on this and then for example let me change the mood
so that we can see the buildings, alright so for example if the clear is walking on this
let me select it, okay change this layer to default and for the tag make sure that you select
tiles, alright and you can do the same for this cabin as well right here, okay this one
select it, make sure it is set to default and then tag will be tiles, alright and then
you can do the same right here as well, actually we can just leave this on default and then
okay let us select tiles on this bridge as well, okay the same right here as well default
and then tiles, alright so you can go ahead and search the whole environment and add these
footsteps in all of them, okay in different places make sure that you tag them correctly
so that specific footsteps sound are played there now if you go ahead and start the game
alright these are the zombie footsteps sound we didn't change it to 3d that's why we are
able to hear it right here but if you walk we can hear the footsteps sound okay let's
select all of these zombies, go inside audio source, make sure that you make this 3d and make the
mix distance as we just say 60, alright now let's play it again, alright now with the game start let's walk
okay the footsteps sound is playing now let's test this
where it is playing the footsteps sounds right here as well and on the cross as well as you can see
now it's test the zombies so if you walk closer to the zombies right there they are going inside
the water, okay here it is as you can see the zombie footsteps sound is playing, okay so it's working
perfectly fine we just have to decrease the player footsteps sound because it is too loud let me
actually play the game and we can test it in real time okay here we are let's make this 3d
alright when we make it 3d now let's click on volume
I think 0.4 is a good value for this, yep now let's test the zombie
there it is okay so the footsteps sound is playing perfectly fine, alright so you can then select
the player, make it 3d, make the volume 0.5 and that will be it